Simon Wang | Toronto, ON | Tel: 647-519-3766

Email: mtwangyugeng@gmail.com | Web: mtwangyugeng.github.io/personalpage

GitHub: github.com/mtwangyugeng | Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/yu-geng-wang-474553192

Skills and Summary

Recent graduate with CS and Math Major. I have strong knowledge of software fundamentals such as data structures, algorithm design, design patterns in object-oriented programming, functional programming, and operating systems I am doing the LeetCode competitions biweekly to have my skill constantly tested. I have many experiences in agile development projects in academic settings. I demonstrated that I can lead/manage scrums under Agile methodologies. Recently I became interested in web development after my friend introduced me to React.js in Dec. 2020. Now I am self-learning about web development	Software Dev JavaScript HTML/CSS Java React.js SQL/MySQL C/Shell Git/ Github Python Andriod Studio	Others Word PowerPoint Excel LaTex Kanban/Trello Slack Discord Bot
,	Terminal	

Relevant Experience

Participated in the course project contest with a group of five; Using an agile development cycle, we developed an application for statistics students and instructors to manage their work. (Oct 2017 - Dec 2017)

SSH

- Made up user stories and tasks based on the client's needs
- Used spreadsheets to manage tasks weekly
- Developed the front end of the app using Java's Jswing library
- Linked the MySQL database APIs to the front end

Learned and Recreated the mechanics of operating systems on Linux (Apr 2018 - Aug 2018)

- Reproduced concepts of operating systems such as synchronization, memory management, process management, file system, pipe, etc. using C.
- Learned to use SSH
- Used visual sandbox to run the reproduced code

Led a group of four to design a new interface for Toad for Oracle, including an interactive prototype and software tutorial. (April 2018 - Aug 2018)

- Interviewed two Database Management software users for our data gathering
- Rolled out details for our GUI's requirements
- Gathered Data (with interviews and artifacts) from potential clients
- Created GUI prototype and tutorials using interactive elements of PowerPoint
- Evaluated our interface prototype based on the traversing times and user feedbacks

Participated in group projects simulating an open-source contribution process for the popular python library matplotlib (Jan 2019 - Mar 2019):

- Took on the position of scrum master for two working weeks
- Followed agile development process and meeting minutes
- Wrote reports on the object-oriented design patterns and open-source contribution processes of matplotlib
- Provided detailed reports, manual, and convincing acceptance/ unit tests for the issues we have chosen to contribute.

Education

Simon Wang | Toronto, ON | Tel: 647-519-3766

Email: mtwangyugeng@gmail.com | Web: mtwangyugeng.github.io/personalpage

GitHub: github.com/mtwangyugeng | Linkedin: linkedin.com/in/yu-geng-wang-474553192

Graduate - Honours Bachelor of Science (BS)
Major in Computer Science and Major in Mathematics